Pierrick Catalo

438-884-9356 | pcatalo@gmail.com | pierrickcatalo.com | linkedin.com/in/pierrickcatalo | github.com/PierrickPro

PROFILE

Passionate about problem solving and helping people with great software. Computer Science BSc from Concordia University. More than 3 years of work experience as back-end developer, program analyst and software developer intern.

Fluent French and English, Intermediate Spanish

Programming: JavaScript/TypeScript, C#/.NET, Java, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS

Technologies: AWS, DevSecOps, Node.js, Docker, Angular, GitLab, CI/CD, SQL Server, Jira, Agile Scrum

Global mindset with experience abroad

EXPERIENCE

Back-End Developer

June 2022 - May 2023

Montreal, QC, Canada

Ubisoft Montreal, Online Services

- Collaborated with a team to develop, operate, maintain and test an AWS pub-sub microservices notification system handling over a million notifications per minute for Online Services
- Optimised cost and performance by integrating new features into our node.js/Java services, and deploying additional AWS Lambdas and Step Functions
- Enhanced system efficiency by creating a JavaScript AWS MSK (Kafka) CDK Construct library, replacing Kinesis Data Streams and improving overall performance
- Streamlined incident management by building a library to route SNS CloudWatch Logs to MS Teams, facilitating efficient communication and response to system incidents
- Applied DevSecOps principles and successfully implemented Test Driven Development (TDD), while actively contributing to projects following Agile and Scrum methodologies

Program Analyst

Aug 2020 – Apr 2022

Randstad Canada, Business Control Team

Montreal, QC, Canada

- Led the end-to-end data integration lifecycle for business analysts in the business control team, covering design, development, implementation, and ongoing support
- Developed C#/Python ETLs to integrate data from 10+ source applications, using diverse Open REST APIs and Selenium for web scraping
- Built a KPI tracker ensuring timely notifications to business analysts based on predefined conditions using C# and SQL Server
- Constructed and maintained Power BI and Looker Studio reports, delivering valuable insights for informed decision-making

Software Developer Internship

Sept 2019 – Aug 2020

Randstad Canada, Operation Team

Montreal, QC, Canada

- Developed automation tools, adeptly translating complex business requirements into efficient technical solutions for cross-functional teams across the company
- Automated Google Workspace workflows using Google App Script (JavaScript) and Google's API
- Developed user-friendly C# utilities for streamlined data tasks involving Excel, Google Sheets, and SQL Server
- Built an Angular/ASP.NET Dashboard to monitor automations using TypeScript/C#

PROJECTS

Crypto Currency Tracker - Telegram Chat Bot | Puthon, Docker, Heroku, REST APIs

- Created a Telegram bot to track ROSE wallet details on Oasis Network, deployed on Heroku with PostgreSQL
- Created a shell script for streamlined Docker deployment and implemented log monitoring for the project

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science

Concordia University

Montreal, QC, Canada

Sept 2018 - Apr 2022

Web Programming, OOP (Java, C++), Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Networks, Distributed Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Information System Security

C Programming Bootcamp (Piscine)

Paris, France

Ecole 42

 $Aug\ 2018$

4 weeks of intensive coding in C, P2P learning methodology, individual and group projects (Bash Script, Vim, Git)